<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<data>
    <p>
        <text>1.) Bring your water to a stable, rolling boil and slowly add your 30 min hop addition (watch for boilover) and start your timer for 30 min. While boiling, sanitize any equipment that will come into
            contact with your wort after the boil:
            a. Measure 5 gallons of water and pour 1 oz (two capfuls) of Io-Star sanitizer into your
            fermentor (mark the 5 gal level on the outside of your carboy) and allow to sit for 1 min.
            b. Use auto-siphon to rack the sanitizer into a spare bucket or tub and use to sanitize rest of
            equipment:
            i. Funnel, airlock, stopper, and wine thief</text>
        <time>30</time>
    </p>
    <p>
        <text>2.) With 15 min left until the end of your boil, pause your timer and turn the flame off to halt the boil,
            then add your malt extract. Be sure to pour slowly and stir constantly to ensure all extract (DME)
            dissolves completely. Once fully dissolved, turn the heat back on. Watch for boil-overs again, as they
            become more likely the more extract you add.
            • Have countermeasures for boil-over ready:
            i. Be prepared to turn the heat down or off.
            ii. Have a spray bottle of water ready to help keep foam at bay.
            3.) Once you’re back up to a stable boil, restart your timer and start prepping your ice bath.
            4.) At 0 min turn off the heat; add “flame out” hop addition and rice syrup solids.</text>
        <time>15</time>
    </p>
    <p>
        <text>1.) Transfer the hot kettle from the burner to a sink or tub filled with cool water.
            2.) Swirl the pot to better cool the wort inside.
            3.) Using ice is more effective if you wait to add it until the wort has cooled significantly. As the water
            becomes hot, refill your tub with cool water until the wort gets down to around 150F. Getting from
            150F to 90F with just cool water takes a while; this is where you want to add the ice.
            4.) Once your wort has cooled to 90F or less, vigorously pour it into your sanitized fermentor. Top off
            your fermentor to 5 gal with the prepped 3 gallons cold water. If the water you add isn’t completely
            cold, wait until your wort is cooled down to 80F or less before pouring it into your carboy.
            5.) Shake the carboy for a few minutes to oxygenate and evenly mix the water with your wort. If you’re
            planning to take a hydrometer reading, do so here before you pitch the yeast.</text>
        <time>110</time>
    </p>
</data>